<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://seedstack.org/archives/16.7/zones/glossary/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://seedstack.org/archives/16.7/zones/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>http://seedstack.org/archives/16.7/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seedstack.org/archives/16.7/glossary/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;anemic-domain-model&#34;&gt;Anemic domain model&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An anti-pattern where the domain objects have hardly any behavior. Frequently they are just data holders with
getter/setter access and the logic completely lives in services on top of the domain objects. This is contrary to the
essence of object-oriented design which is to combine data and behavior together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anti-pattern is really a procedural design in disguise. It has the cost of a good domain model but none of the benefits.
Read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/AnemicDomainModel.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bounded-context&#34;&gt;Bounded context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bounded context is a pattern of the &lt;a href=&#39;http://seedstack.org/archives/16.7/glossary#strategic-design&#39;&gt;strategic design&lt;/a&gt; aspect of the DDD which is about dealing with large
models and teams. Large models are divided into different bounded contexts and are being explicit about their
interrelationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cqrs&#34;&gt;CQRS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Command Query Responsibility Segregation (CQRS) pattern is a notion that a different model can be used to update
information (command model) than the model used for reading information (query model).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;domain&#34;&gt;Domain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sphere of knowledge, influence or activity. The subject area to which the user applies a program is the
domain of the software. The domain is completely agnostic of the application logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;domain-driven-design&#34;&gt;Domain-Driven Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An approach to the development of complex software adding on OOP to allow designers to concentrate on Business concerns rather than infrastructure ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;model&#34;&gt;Model&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An abstraction (eg. class diagram, mind map, plain text) that describes a domain and can be used to solve
problems related to that domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;principal&#34;&gt;Principal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a security context, a &lt;em&gt;principal&lt;/em&gt; is a defining characteristic of a subject that can be uniquely identified, like an
identifier, a name, a social-security number, a language, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spi&#34;&gt;SPI&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Service Provider Interface (SPI) is an API intended to be implemented or extended by a third party. It can be used to
enable framework extension and replaceable components. SeedStack provides numerous SPI, allowing the developer to extend
its capabilities and behaviors when needed. In SeedStack, all SPI live in a specific subpackage named &lt;code&gt;*.spi&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;strategic-design&#34;&gt;Strategic design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategic Design is a set of principles for maintaining model integrity, distillation of the Domain Model and working
with multiple models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ubiquitous-language&#34;&gt;Ubiquitous Language&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common, rigorous language build up between developers and domain experts. This language should be based on the Domain
Model used in the software. It should evolve as the team&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the domain grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;value-object&#34;&gt;Value object&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objects holding related values and defined by them. They have no identity, meaning that two value objects holding the same
values are equals. They should be immutable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>